AHMED YUSSUF

Ahmedyussuf2099@gmail.com | 207-376-7633 Lewiston, ME 04240

EDUCATION

Southern Maine Community College - South Portland, ME Current

Associate of Science: Computer Science

The University of Maine at Augusta - Augusta, ME 12/2020

Bachelor of Science: Mental Health and Human Services

Central Maine Community College - Auburn, ME 05/2018

Associate of Science: Human Services

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-focused Web Developer Intern with experience in web-based applications. Participated in the development and implementation of web-based solutions.

Exceptionally creative and dependable entry-level web developer with outstanding knowledge of HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript.

Accomplished Program Coordinator offering experience implementing new and innovative programs aimed at meeting the needs of the consumer.

SKILLS

- Landing Page Development
- Responsive Web Design
- Time Management
- Web Practice Guidance
- HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript.

- Photoshop
- Java
- Code Validation
- Excellent Problem-Solving Skills
- Bootstrap

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelancer-Front End Web Developer | Self-Employer 06/2021 - Current

- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS.
- Effectively use industry-standard code editing software.
- Edit, crop, resize, adjust and retouch photographic and digitally generated images for the web.
- Work with various files such as cascading style sheets and HTML documents
- Integrate various web technologies such as CSS into a working, online website.
- Become familiar with current hosting solutions Work with File Transfer Protocol.
- Provided technical help for troubleshooting technical issues related to HTML templates.

Youth Worker | Day One - Portland, ME

07/2022 - Current

- Managed and led activities promoting growth in mental, emotional, and educational areas.
- Completed necessary reports and documentation to maintain thorough, accurate case records.
- Encouraged youth clients to develop their activities and leadership skills through group discussions.
- Provided key emotional support to special needs youth.
- Scheduled and accompanied youth clients to outside appointments such as therapy sessions, medical appointments, and social outings.
- Challenged youth to accomplish motor development goals and inspire a love of movement and healthy habits.
- Assisted families in developing and maintaining support networks by identifying and utilizing community resources and services.
- Worked with clients to improve life choices and maximize the benefits of programs.
- Collaborated on program operations and relayed participant feedback for improvements.
- Detailed program operations and participant activities with comprehensive recordkeeping.
- Improved clients' coping with routine life activities such as food budgeting and rental payments.

Program Coordinator | Minds for Health LLC - Lewiston, ME 04/2018 - 08/2022

- Provided ongoing direction and leadership for program operations. Scheduled
- and supervised staff meetings to discuss new ideas and update participants on program details and milestones.
- Organized and managed program development from conception through successful execution.
- Designed program implementation and maintenance plan.
- Gathered and organized printed materials required for program participation.
- Developed and organized routine and special programming by factoring in slot timing, demographics, and other important parameters.
- An assessed patient's needs and recommend appropriate courses of treatment. Documented information for charts, progress reports, assessments, and other
- paperwork within specific timeframes.
 Developed individual treatment plans for clients diagnosed with various
- conditions.
 - Responded to crises when severe mental health and behavioral issues arose.
- Partnered with the program director on recommendations, process
- improvements, and corrective action plans.

 Provided client assessments upon admission and discharge. Fostered
- relationships to define programming needs and strengthen
- organizational standing.